Guide to the Ron Offen Papers 1944-2007
University of Chicago Library
Offen, Ron. Papers
1944-2007
19.5 linear feet (37 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
Ron Offen (1930-2010), editor, poet, and librarian. The Ron Offen Papers contain drafts, manuscripts, proofs, book reviews, publications, biographical material, correspondence, photographs, newspaper articles, videocassettes, legal documents, playbills, college course evaluations, and interviews. The papers document Offen's literary and editorial career, primarily his role as editor of the journal Free Lunch: A Poetry Miscellany.
Information on Use
Access
Series III, Subseries 4, Box 34, includes financial material that is restricted until 2047.
Series IV, Audio-Visual, does not include access copies for part or all of the material in this series. Researchers will need to consult with staff before requesting material from this series.
The remainder of the collection is open for research.
Biographical Note
Ron Offen was born to Charles, a sales engineer, and Ellen Offen on October 12, 1930 in Chicago, IL. In 1950 he married Sharon Nealy; from 1966-2000 he was married to Rosine Breuckner (aka Kristine Cameron); in 2003, he married Beverly K. Drick. Offen received an AA degree from Wright Junior College in 1950 and an MA degree from the University of Chicago in 1967.
Offen worked in the insurance industry from 1953-1967. He then pursued a literary career as a poet, writer, and editor. He served as editor for Chicagoland (1967-1969) and Automotive Fleet (1969-1971). In 1994 he edited The Starving Poets' Cookbook, Free Lunch Arts Alliance. He wrote biographies and books of poetry, including Dillinger: Dead or Alive? (with Jay Robert Nash, 1970), Brando (1973), Together: A Casebook of Joint Practices in Primary Care (with Hal Higdon and Jack Star, 1977), Instead of Gifts: Poems for Poets (1995), Answer Questions (1996), and God's Haircut, and other Remembered Dreams (1999).
Offen wrote poetry columns for Chicagoland and Automotive Fleet magazines. He also created several television series including Blackwash, Main Road Travelled, and Meeting of the Mindless, as well as the radio plays The Last Celebration of Leon Duprey, and Madame Sostro: The Dream Merchant.
In 1989, after a bout with cancer, Offen founded the poetry journal Free Lunch: A Poetry Miscellany. He stated, "I thought about how important poetry had been to me my whole life and how much it had given to me. So, I thought, I want to give something back to poetry and poets."
Offen was an active member in various organizations, such as Authors League of America and Society of Mid Land Authors. In 1955 Offen won first prize from the Chicago Poets and Writers Association and in 1975 he won the Joseph Jefferson Award for producer of children's theater.
Offen continued to edit Free Lunch: A Poetry Miscellany until it ceased publication in 2009. He died on August 9, 2010.
Scope Note
The Ron Offen Papers are organized into four series: Series I, Manuscripts and Personal; Series II, Correspondence; Series III, Free Lunch: A Poetry Miscellany; and Series IV, Audio-Visual. The Papers contain drafts, manuscripts, proofs, book reviews, publications, biographical material, correspondence, photographs, newspaper articles, videocassettes, legal documents, playbills, college course evaluations, and interviews.
Series I, Manuscripts and Personal, contains manuscripts, drafts, proofs, notes, photographs, press clippings, legal documents, interviews, and reviews of Offen's books, Brando and Dillinger: Dead or Alive?. There are two movie scripts, Four Play and Good and Plenty; manuscripts of his television series Blackwash, Main Road Travelled, and Meeting of the Mindless. His plays The Last Celebration of Leon Duprey and Madame Sostro: The Dream Merchant were aired on several radio stations. There are playbills from theaters located in the Chicagoland Area. Also included are course evaluations from 1978-1979 when he taught a health science class at Saddleback College. Offen wrote a poetry column, and some of his topics included A day for the love of Poetry, and She's Lisel Mueller, a gifted prizewinner. Offen interviewed Maria Fornes in 1972 about being an Obie-honored off Broadway playwright. See Box 24 for oversize materials.
Series II, Correspondence, is arranged chronologically. Most of the correspondence is from Offen's role as editor of Free Lunch and includes letters from poets and colleagues, manuscript submissions, and correspondence about fund drive events. Other correspondence discusses Offen's manuscripts and publications. See Subseries II and Series III for additional correspondence.
Frequent correspondents include Gerry Adler, Eric Alterman, Mike Amato, Donna Biffar, Arthur Binard, Norbert Blei, Jared Carter, Raphael Catala, Fiona Cooper, Kevin Coyne, Bob Davies, Gilbert Dilen, Chris Dombrowski, Thomas Dorsett, Stephen Duplij, Dave Etter, Raymond Farr, Ruth E. Foley, Arthur Foote, Arthur C. Ford, Jerry Friedman, Kathleen Gilbert, Dana Gioia, Joseph Green, John Gribble, Ian Haight, Donald Hall, Donna Henning, Glenn Ingersoll, Colin James, David Jewell, Robert K. Johnson, Jim Kates, Michael Krammer, Thomas Kretz, Richard Krohn, Wendy Lesser, Christina Liggins, Warden Mamie Lockett, Glenna Luschei, Warden Mike Madding, Joe Massey, Kerry McCaskill, W.S. Merwin, Chelle Miko, Penelope Moffet, Matt Morris, C. Mulrooney, David Offutt, Robert Peters, Christopher Presfield, Hilda Raz, James Reiss, Julia Ridl, Fernand Roqueplan, Brian Russell, Mona San Pedro, James Scofield, David Allen Sheldon, Cathy Song, T.K. Splake, Beth Campbell Stemple, Iron Thunderhorse, Larry Tomoyasu, David Vancil, Frank Van Zant, Nick Vittum, Michael Walls, Mary Ann Wehler, J.D. Whitney, and Lois-Ann Yamanaka.
Series III, Free Lunch: A Poetry Miscellany, is arranged into four subseries. Subseries 1, Journal Issues, contains correspondence, manuscripts, proofs, and submissions of the publications. Subseries 2, Starving Poets' Cookbook, Free Lunch Arts Alliance, includes correspondence, proofs, orders, manuscripts, drafts, and marketing material for the publication. Subseries 3, Administrative and Events, includes articles, correspondence, fliers, brochures, and other ephemera on poets, poetry readings, fundraising events, and workshops. Other administrative documents include information about subscriptions, awards, grants, contests, annual reports, and articles of incorporation. See Box 24 for oversize materials.
Series III, Subseries 4, Expenses, includes budgets and receipts. Box 33 includes financial material that is restricted until 2047.
Series IV, Audio-Visual, includes videocassettes of poetry readings sponsored by Free Lunch as well as Offen's plays, The Last Celebration of Leon Duprey, and Madame Sostro: The Dream Merchant.
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
Subject Headings
Offen, Ron; American poetry--20th century; American poetry--21st century; American poetry -- 20th century -- Periodicals; American poetry -- 21st century -- Periodicals; American literature -- 20th century -- Periodicals; American literature -- 21st century -- Periodicals; Poetry, Modern--20th century; Poetry, Modern--20th century--Periodicals; Small Presses
INVENTORY
- Series I: Manuscripts and Personal
  - Blackwash, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Blackwash, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brando, Contract, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Brando, Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Brando, Interviews, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Brando, Jacket Design, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Brando, Manuscripts, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Brando, Manuscripts, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Brando, Manuscripts, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Brando, Manuscripts, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Brando, Manuscripts, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Brando, Manuscripts, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Brando, Manuscripts, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Brando, Manuscripts, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Brando, Manuscripts, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Brando, Manuscripts, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Brando, Outline, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Brando, Photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Brando, Promotion, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Brando, Proof, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Brando, Research, 1944-1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Brando, Research, 1944-1958 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Brando, Research, 1944-1958 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Brando, Research, 1950-1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Brando, Research, 1954-1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Brando, Research, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Brando, Research, 1973-1976 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Brando, Research, 1973-1976 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Brando, Reviews, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Dillinger: Dead or Alive?, Final Draft, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Dillinger: Dead or Alive?, Legal Documents, 1969-1990 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Dillinger: Dead or Alive?, Legal Documents, 1969-1990 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Dillinger: Dead or Alive?, Newspaper Articles, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Dillinger: Dead or Alive?, Newspaper Articles, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Dillinger: Dead or Alive?, Original Draft, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Dillinger: Dead or Alive?, Original Draft, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Four Play, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Four Play, 1971-1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Four Play, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Four Play, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Four Play, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Good and Plenty, 1978-1996 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Good and Plenty, 1978-1996 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Good and Plenty, 1978-1996 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Good and Plenty, Final First Draft, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Good and Plenty, Final First Draft, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Good and Plenty, Final First Draft, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Good and Plenty, Revisions, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Good and Plenty, Revisions, 1988-1991 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Good and Plenty, Scene Summary, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Good and Plenty, Synopsis, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Interview with Maria Forens, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Last Celebration of Leon Duprey, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Madame Sostro: The Dream Merchant, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Main Travelled Roads, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Meeting of the Mindless, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Columns, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Playbills, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Saddleback College Course Evaluations, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Series II: Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1959-1993 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence and Acceptance Forms, 1992-1997 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence and Acceptance Forms, 1992-1997 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence and Acceptance Forms, 1992-1997 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Prisoner Issue, 1996-1997 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Prisoner Issue, 1996-1997 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Prisoner Issue, 1996-1997 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 2000-2001 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2000-2001 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Series III: Free Lunch: A Poetry Miscellany
  - Subseries 1: Journal Issues
    - Issue #1, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Issue #1, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Issue #2, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Issue #2, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Issue #2, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Issue #2, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Issue #3, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Issue #3, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Issue #4, 1989-1990 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Issue #4, 1989-1990 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Issue #4, 1989-1990 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Issue #5, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Issue #5, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Issue #5, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Issue #6, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Issue #6, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Issue #6, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Issue #7, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Issue #7, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Issue #7, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Issue #8, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Issue #8, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Issue #9, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Issue #9, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Issue #9, 1991-1992 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Issue #9, 1991-1992 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Issue #10, 1991-1992 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Issue #10, 1991-1992 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Issue #11, 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Issue #11, 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Issue #12, 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Issue #12, 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Issue #12, 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Issue #12, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Issue #13, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Issue #13, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Issue #13, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Issue #14, 1992-1994 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Issue #14, 1992-1994 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Issue #15, 1994-1995 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Issue #15, 1994-1995 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Issue #16, 1995-1996 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Issue #16, 1995-1996 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Issue #17, Secret Issue, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Issue #17, Secret Issue, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Issue #18, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Issue #18, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Issue #19, 1996-1997 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Issue #19, 1996-1997 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Issue #20, Prisoner Issue, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Issue #20, Prisoner Issue, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Issue #20, Prisoner Issue, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Issue #20, Prisoner Issue, 1997-1998 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Issue #20, Prisoner Issue, 1997-1998 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Issue #21, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Issue #22, 1998-1999 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Issue #22, 1998-1999 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Issue #23, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Issue #23, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Issue #24, 1999-2000 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Issue #24, 1999-2000 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Issue #25, 2000-2001 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Issue #25, 2000-2001 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Issue #26, 2000-2001 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Issue #26, 2000-2001 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Issue #26, 2000-2001 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Issue #27, 2001 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Issue #27, 2001 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Issue #27, 2001 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Issue #28, 2001-2002 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Issue #28, 2001-2002 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Issue #28, 2001-2002 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Issue #29, 2002-2003 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Issue #29, 2002-2003 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Issue #30, 2002-2003 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Issue #30, 2002-2003 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Issue #31, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Issue #31, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Issue #31, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Issue #32, 2004-2005 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Issue #32, 2004-2005 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Issue #32, 2004-2005 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Issue #33, 2005 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Issue #33, 2005 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Issue #33, 2005 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Issue #34, 2005 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Issue #34, 2005 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Issue #34, 2005 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Issue #35, 2006 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Issue #35, 2006 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Issue #36, undated (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Issue #2, 1989 (Box 24 [OVERSIZE], Folder 1)
    - Issue #3, 1989 (Box 24 [OVERSIZE], Folder 2)
    - Issue #4, 1989-1990 (Box 24 [OVERSIZE], Folder 3)
    - John Dillinger Poster, undated (Box 24 [OVERSIZE], Folder 4)
    - Proofs, Brando, 1973 (Box 24 [OVERSIZE], Folder 5)
    - Proofs, Brando, 1973 (Box 24 [OVERSIZE], Folder 6)
  - Subseries 2: Starving Poets' Cookbook, Free Lunch Arts Alliance
    - Approach Reprints, 1959 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Designs, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Distributors, 1994-1995 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Guidelines, 1993-1994 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Marketing, 1994-1996 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Marketing, 1994-1996 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Orders, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Proofs, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Proofs, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Proofs, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Proofs, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Reviews, 1993-1997 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Reviews, 1993-1997 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Reviews, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Reviews, 2006 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - R.W. Bowker, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 3: Administrative and Events
    - Annual Balance Sheets, 2004-2006 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Annual Reports, 1999-2000 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Articles, 2003-2004 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Articles of Corporation and By-Laws, Illinois, 2005 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Barilla America Contest, 2003-2004 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - California Arts Council, 1991-1994 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - California Dissolution, 2004-2005 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Council of Literary Magazines and Presses Grants, 1980-1996 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - COSMEP, 1993 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Display Signs, 2006 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Forms, 1995-2006 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Free Lunch Radio Program, 2000-2003 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Fund Drive, 1989-1992 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Fund Drive, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Fund Drive, 1993 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Fund Drive, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Fund Drive, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Fund Drive, 1996-1999 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Fund Drive, 1996-1999 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Fund Drive, 2000 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Fund Drive, 2001 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Fund Drive, 2002 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Fund Drive, 2002 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Fund Drive, 2003 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Fund Drive, 2004 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Fund Drive, 2004 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Fund Drive, 2005 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Fund Drive, 2006 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Fund Drive, 2007 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Illinois Arts Council Grant, 2005 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Illinois Arts Council Grant, 2006 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Illinois Arts Council Literary Awards, 2005-2006 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Invoices, 2005 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Mentor Series, 2001-2006 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Midwest Literary Festival, 2003 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Newsletter, 2004 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Non-fundraising, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Photograph, Berkley, Ann, undated (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Photograph, Offen, Ron, undated (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Poetry Magazine, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Poetry Magazine, 1987-1988 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Poetry Off the Page, 2006 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Poetry Reading, Daigon, Ruth, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Poetry Reading, Fearing, Kenneth, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Poetry Reading, Glenview, 2003 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Poetry Reading, Glenview, 2003 (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Poetry Reading, Glenview, 2003-2004 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Poetry Reading, Glenview, 2003-2004 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Poetry Reading, Glenview, 2003-2004 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Poetry Reading, Glenview, 2003-2004 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Poetry Reading, Glenview, 2004 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Poetry Reading, Glenview, 2005 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Poetry Reading, Laguna Niguel, 1997 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Poetry Reading, Laguna Niguel, 1997 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Poetry Reading, Laguna Niguel, 1997 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Poetry Reading, Laguna Niguel, 1997 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Poetry Reading, Laguna Niguel, 1997 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Poetry Reading, Laguna Niguel, 1997 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Poetry Reading, Mission Viejo, 1996-1997 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Poetry Reading, Mission Viejo, 1996-1997 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Poetry Reading, Mission Viejo, 1998-1999 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Poetry Reading, Ridge, Lola, 1929-1995 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Poetry Reading, Wilmette, 2003-2004 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Poetry Reading, Wilmette, 2003-2005 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Poetry Reading, Wilmette, 2004 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Poetry Reading, Wilmette, 2004-2005 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Poetry Reading, Wilmette, 2004-2005 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Poetry Reading, Wilmette, 2005 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Poetry Reading, Wilmette, 2005-2006 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Poetry Reading, Wilmette, 2006 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Pushcart Prize, 2000-2006 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Reprise Series, 2003 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Rosaline Offen Memorial Award, undated (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Submissions, undated (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Subscriptions, 1989-1993 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Subscriptions, 2006 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - T.S. Eliot Project, 2005-2006 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - T-Shirts, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Unpublished Poet Proposal, 1989-1991 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Unpublished Poet Proposal, 1997 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Web Design, 2000-2005 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Workshops, 2003 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 4: Expenses [RESTRICTED]
    - Expenses, 1987-1990 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Expenses, 1991 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Expenses, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Expenses, 1993 (Box 34, Folder 4)